how to connect powerbi Telemetry apps to
read your Telemetry data in aure
application insights when you have
installed the powerbi app for business
business Central Telemetry whether it is
for environments or for apps you notice
that you see the app with sample data
but you of course would like to see this
with your data so how do you do that
well you see this Banner in yellow on
the top if you click connect your data
you get a menu where you need to set
certain things the most important thing
you need to set is the application
insights application ID and this uh
where do you get this ID from because
this is you specifying where is my data
let me show you
where you find the application insights
application
ID um under the API menu to the left so
let me scroll down here on the menu on
the left a little bit scroll scroll
scroll scroll scroll here and then under
the configure menu there's a menu called
API access let's go here and this is
where the application ID resides you
need for your power pi to connect to
your data so you simply take this guid
on the right hand side I can copy to
clipboard let me copy that and then go
back to powerbi to insert
that so back in powerbi I copi the
application insights application ID guid
there you go I will probably also set
the time zone so my customer is located
in Copenhagen so I set the time zone of
the report to to Copenhagen and then the
only other thing I need to set is the
look back period when the when the
report refreshes you can set a weekly or
daily or a monthly so it every night it
will refresh with that look back period
let's just pick two weeks and click next
and the the only other thing I need for
this report to start set up nightly
refresh is I need to authentic at to um
to application insights using or so
there will come a small menu up here in
a second there you go so I need to pick
o or two and then I need to Simply say
sign in and connect when I do that I
will be prompted for my uh authorization
so I will click
here and uh that's it
now the powerbi report is authorized to
refresh as me and uh you can see that um
this will start uh uh refreshing you can
see the banner here is changing to
refresh is in progress and you're all
[Music]
set